A Guide to the Governor Robert F. McDonnell, Policy Office, Records, 1997; 2007-2014 (bulk 2010-2013)
Library of Virginia
- III. Judicial Appointments, 2010-2013., Extent: 2.1 cubic feet (6 boxes). (Box 51-56)
  - Subseries III.B. Virginia Court of Appeals, 2011; 2013., Extent: 0.35 cubic feet (1 box) (Box 53)
    - Smith, Robert J., 2013. (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Subseries III.C. Circuit Court, 2010; 2012-2013., Extent: 1.05 cubic feet (3 boxes) (Box 54-56)
    - Correspondence from the Supreme Court of Virginia pertaining to Circuit Court vacancies, 2010; 2012. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Judges, 2012. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Judicial Selection, Circuit Court Judge, Sixth Judicial Circuit, 2012. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Judicial Selection, Circuit Court Judge, Tenth Judicial Circuit (1 of 2), 2012. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Judicial Selection, Circuit Court Judge, Tenth Judicial Circuit (2 of 2), 2012. (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Judicial Selection, Circuit Court Judge, 29th Judicial Circuit, 2012. (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Atwill, William, 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Barclay, Robert C., Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Barredo, David M., 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Bates, Al W., Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Batliner, Ronald, Fourth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Bland, Denise, Second Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Boynton, Christopher S., Second Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Brewbaker, Robert S., Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Casey, Brian N., Fourth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Chupik, Elizabeth, Fourth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Crowe, Joel P., Third Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Frucci, Steve, Second Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Griffin, Diane, Third Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Heretick, Stephen, Third Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Holland, Helivi, Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Irby, Jeanette, 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Jones, Jr., Robert W., Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Lannetti, David W., Fourth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Love, Tate C., 25th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - McCausland, Linda, Second Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Meals, Bryan K., Third Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Mooney, J. Gregory, 25th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Paice, Rhonda, 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Pishko, Bernard A., Fourth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 24)
    - Ricketts, III, Charles L., 25th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - Sandwich, Jr., Robert H., Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - Shah, Rupen R., 25th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - Sincavage, Steve E., 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - Sinclair, Lorrie A., 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Sprinkle, J. Wayne, Third Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Stein, Edward K., 25th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Thomas, III, C.J. Steuart, 25th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Thompson, Zaida, 20th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Weaver, Sonya, Third and Fifth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Whitlow, Morton V., Third Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Wilcox, Bruce A., Fourth Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Info on the 25th Judicial Circuit, 2012. (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Info on the 28th Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Info on the 31st Judicial Circuit, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Subseries III.D. District Court, 2011., Extent: 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Anderson, Timothy V., 2011. (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence from the Virginia State Bar, 2013. (Box 56, Folder 13)
- IV. Subject Files, 1997; 2007-2014 (bulk 2010-2013)., Extent: 18.5 cubic feet (53 boxes). (Box 57-109)
  The Subject Files series is housed in 53 boxes and is arranged into nine (9) subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. Jasen Eige, Counselor to the Governor and Senior Policy Advisor; B. Jeff Palmore, Director of Policy Development and Deputy Counselor; C. Melissa Laughner, Deputy Director of Policy; D. Julia Ciarlo Hammond, Director of Legislative Affairs and Policy Advisor; E. Generra Peck, Special Assistant for Policy Development and Deputy Director of Legislative Affairs and Policy Development; F. Christy Morton, Deputy Director of External Affairs and Policy Development; G. Chad Cole, Scheduling Assistant, Deputy Travel Aide and Policy Assistant; H. Policy Files; and I. Records Transferred by Northam Administration. These files include correspondence, memorandums, email, legislative files, budget documents, briefs, meeting records, presentations, reports, talking points, executive orders, and invitations. This series documents the work of individual members of the Policy Office and the McDonnell administration's policy initiatives. Those initiatives include, but are not limited to: Alcoholic Beverage Control (ABC) privatization, energy policy, Governor's Commission on Economic Development and Job Creation, Governor's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring, Governor's Commission on Higher Education, Innovation and Investment, Governor's Task Force for Local Government Mandate Review, health care, transportation reform, and Virginia Retirement System (VRS) reform.
  - Subseries IV.A. Jasen Eige, Counselor to the Governor and Senior Policy Advisor, 2010-2013., Extent: 4.9 cubic feet (12 boxes) (Box 57-68)
    This subseries is housed in 12 boxes. The original file order has been maintained. On 12 January 2010, Governor-elect Robert F. McDonnell appointed J. Jasen Eige as Counselor and Senior Advisor to the Governor. Eige's duties included providing legal counsel and advice to the Governor and his Administration, and assisting with policy and legislative matters. Governor McDonnell promoted Eige to Counselor and Senior Policy Advisor in June 2011. In this cabinet-level position, Eige oversaw the Governor's Policy Office, including the direction of the administration's policy and legislative efforts.
    Eige's files contain records related to a wide variety of subjects and issues faced by McDonnell administration including the development of McDonnell's state budget and legislative agenda, education, government, regulatory, tax, transportation and retirement reform, energy policy, and uranium.
    - Budget Documents, 2014-2016 Budget
      - Budget Meeting, 12 November 2013. (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Budget Meeting, 5 November 2013. (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Budget Meeting, 30 October 2013. (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Budget Meeting, 22 October 2013. (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Budget Meeting, 10 October 2013. (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Budget Meeting, 19 September 2013. (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Budget Items Impacting Homelessness, September 2013. (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - The Virginia Rebuilding Family Bridges Program, September 2013. (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Budget Documents, 2013 Amendments
      - Budget Documents, 2012-2013. (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Budget Documents, November and December 2012. (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Budget Documents, November and December 2012. (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Budget Documents, October and November 2012. (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Budget Documents, August to October 2012 and undated. (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - 2012-2014 Budget
      - 2012-2014 Biennial Budget and Amendments to the Appropriation Act, 19 December 2011. (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Budget Documents, 2011 Amendments
      - Budget Documents, December 2010. (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Budget Documents, 2010 Amendments
      - Budget Amendments, April 2010. (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - 2012 General Assembly Session
      - Prior Policy Documents, May 2011. (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Policy Agenda, May-September 2011. (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Policy Work Groups, July 2011. (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - 2012 Policy Development, 2011. (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Policy Meeting, November 2011. (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - 2012 Policy Strategy, 2011-2012. (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Government Reform (Plan and Outreach), 2011. (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - Pre-Session and 2012 General Assembly Session Timeline, December 2011. (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Cabinet Meeting Agenda and Handouts, 9 January 2012. (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - State of the Commonwealth Address, 1st and 6th Drafts, January 2012. (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Governor McDonnell's Key Legislative Issues for 2012 General Assembly, 2012. (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Governor's Bills, 2012. (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Crossover Status Update, February 2012. (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - 2012 End of Session, March 2012. (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - SB 349 Conscience Clause Bill. (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - SB 484 Ultrasound Bill, 2012. (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - HB 1106. (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - HB 1160, April 2012. (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Post-Session Outreach, 2012. (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - 2012 General Assembly Session - Subject Files
      - Agriculture and Forestry, 2011. (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - CRM Development, 2012. (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Economic Development Budget, 2011. (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Energy, 2011. (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Government Reform (1 of 3), 2011. (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Government Reform (2 of 3), 2011. (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - Government Reform (3 of 3), 2011. (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Intellectual Property Project, 2011-2012. (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - K-12 Education, 2011-2012. (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Local Mandates on Localities, 2012. (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Public Safety, 2011-2012. (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Small Business, 2011. (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Tax Reform, 2011. (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Tax Reform, 2011-2012. (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Tax Reform, 2011. (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Transportation, 2011-2012. (Box 61, Folder 8)
      - Veterans, 2011. (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Virginia Retirement System (VRS) Reform, 2011-2012. (Box 61, Folder 10)
      - Voter Identification Legislation, 2012 Session. (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - 2013 General Assembly Session - Subject Files
      - Accomplishments, 2012. (Box 61, Folder 12)
      - Bill Signing Ceremonies, 2013. (Box 61, Folder 13)
      - Binder of J. Jasen Eige, 2012-2013. (Box 61, Folder 14)
      - Energy, 2012. (Box 61, Folder 15)
      - Government Reform Legislative Package, 2013. (Box 61, Folder 16)
      - Governor's Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates (GACRE), 19 November 2012. (Box 61, Folder 17)
      - Governor's Agenda, 19 November 2012. (Box 61, Folder 18)
      - Governor's Amendments Talking Points, House Version, Veto Session, April 2013. (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Governor's Jobs Agenda Update, February 2013. (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - House Leadership Meeting, 9 August 2012. (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - K-12 Education Reform
        - A-F Grading of Schools, 2013. (Box 62, Folder 4)
        - Education Budget Amendments, 2013. (Box 62, Folder 5)
        - K-12 Education Legislative and Budget Proposals, 2012. (Box 62, Folder 6)
        - Opportunity Education Institution (OEI), 2012-2013. (Box 62, Folder 7)
        - Meetings and Memorandums (1 of 3), 2012. (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - Meetings and Memorandums (2 of 3), 2012. (Box 62, Folder 9)
        - Meetings and Memorandums (3 of 3), 2012. (Box 62, Folder 10)
      - Legislator Roundtables, November 2012. (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Medicaid Expansion/Reform, 2012-2013. (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous Policy and Session Documents, 2012-2013. (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - 2013 Policy Development, 2012. (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Post-Session Outreach, 2013. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Regulatory Reform, 2012-2013. (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - 2013 Session Ideas, 2012. (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Tax Reform, 2012. (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Uranium, 2013. (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Water Quality, 2012. (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Subject Files (General)
      - Abortion Clinic Regulations, 2010; 2012. (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Adoption Regulations, 2011. (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - ABC Retail Privatization Overview, 30 November 2010. (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Americans for Tax Reform, 2012. (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Autism Bill, 2011. (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Center for the Arts at Virginia Tech, Governor's Briefing, 27 September 2010. (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Congressional Delegation Meeting, 18 July 2012. (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Craft Beer, 1 June 2012. (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - Drones, undated. (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Embryonic Stem Cells, 2011. (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Eminent Domain, January 2012. (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - GeoCare, Sexual Violent Predator Proposal, 26 January 2011. (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - The Great Southwest: May 4-5, 2011, Briefing for Jasen Eige. (Box 64, Folder 13)
      - House Bill 1500, 6 February 2011. (Box 64, Folder 14)
      - MWV Thermal Energy, 2011. (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous Loose Documents, 2011-2013. (Box 64, Folder 16)
      - Office of the Inspector General
        - Virginia's Civil Commitment Statutes and Treatment of Sexually Violent Predators, 2011. (Box 65, Folder 1)
        - OIG Report No. 206-11, OIG Review of Emergency Services, 28 February 2012. (Box 65, Folder 2)
        - OIG Report No. 207-12, Review of the Barriers to Discharge in the State-Operated Behavioral Healthcare Adult Facilities, 25 April 2012. (Box 65, Folder 3)
        - OIG Semiannual Report, 1 October 2011-31 March 2012, 17 May 2012. (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Pardon Process, 2010. (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Procurement and Contribution Law, 2011. (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Pro-Life Issues, 2011-2012. (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - REAL ID, 2010. (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Report on Work Groups, 26 July 2011. (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Research and Technology Strategic Initiatives, 2012. (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Mike Reynold Memorandums, 24 June 2011. (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - State Board of Elections (SBE), 2012. (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV) Reform, 2012-2013. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Surface Mining, 2010. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Taxation, Chmura Economics and Analytics, Evaluation of Virginia's Sales Tax Exemptions, 2011. (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Transportation Reform
        - Correspondence and Presentations, September 2012. (Box 66, Folder 5)
        - Tax Reform Alternatives for Funding Transportation, November-December 2012. (Box 66, Folder 6)
        - Tax and Transportation Alternatives, 2013. (Box 66, Folder 7)
        - Transportation Talking Points, 2013. (Box 66, Folder 8)
        - Virginia's Road to the Future: Governor McDonnell's 2013 Legislative Package for Transportation Funding and Reform, 2013. (Box 66, Folder 9)
        - Conference Committee, 2013 Legislative Package for Transportation Funding and Reform, HB 2313 2013. (Box 66, Folder 10)
        - Comparison of Funding, 2013. (Box 67, Folder 1)
        - HB 2313 Floor Amendment n the Nature of a Substitute, 4 February 2013. (Box 67, Folder 2)
        - HB 2313 Amendment Form, undated. (Box 67, Folder 3)
        - HB 2313 edited version with track changes, 17 March 2013. (Box 67, Folder 4)
        - HB 2313 edited version with track changes, 19 March 2013. (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Two-Term Governor, 2010. (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - Uranium, 2012-2013. (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Vets, 2010. (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Center for Behavioral Rehabilitation PPEA, 2012. (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Virginia Retirement System, 2010. (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV.B. Jeff Palmore, Director of Policy Development and Deputy Counselor, 1997; 2007-2008; 2010-2013., Extent: 2.28 cubic feet (7 boxes) (Box 69-75)
    This subseries is housed in seven (7) boxes and arranged alphabetically by subject. On 13 August 2010, Governor Robert F. McDonnell announced the appointment of Jeff Palmore as Deputy Counselor. Palmore formerly worked for McDonnell in the Office of the Attorney General as Special Assistant for Legislative Affairs. Governor McDonnell promoted Palmore to Director of Policy Development and Deputy Counselor in June 2011. Palmore managed the administration's policy formulation and worked with the Cabinet and their staff to implement McDonnell's policy agenda. Palmore served as the Executive Director of the Governor's Commission on Government Reform, Efficiency and Restructuring and oversaw the implementation of Governor McDonnell's coalition outreach. Palmore provided specific management of policy and messaging within the Secretariats of Administration, Commonwealth, Finance and Public Safety. Palmore left the administration in September 2013.
    The bulk of this series is comprised of Palmore's records as Executive Director of the Governor's Commission on Government Reform, Efficiency and Restructuring. It also includes the records of Mike Reynold, the previous executive director of the Commission. Other notable subjects include Alcoholic Beverage Control (ABC) Privatization and Virginia Retirement System (VRS) reform.
    - Abortion Regulations, 2011. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control (ABC) Privatization (1 of 3), 2010-2011. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control (ABC) Privatization (2 of 3), 2010. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control (ABC) Privatization (3 of 3), 2010-2012. (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Budget Veto/Amendment Research, 2011. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Ethics Reform Policy, 2013. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Executive Orders (1 of 3), 2010. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Executive Orders (2 of 3), 2010. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Executive Orders (3 of 3), 2010-2011. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - 2012 General Assembly Session
      - 2012 Legislation Documents, 2011-2012. (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Reconvene Session 2012, Governor's Amendments and Veto Key Points, 2012. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Geospatial Services in Virginia, 2012. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Government Reform (Files of Michael Reynold, Deputy Director of Policy)
      - Executive Directive 2, 2011. (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Boards and Commissions, 2011. (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Local Government Reform, undated. (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - CSB Reform, undated. (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Executive Order 2, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Opera Solutions - Lottery Privatization, 2011. (Box 71, Folder 6)
      - Consolidation of Taxes, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - 2010 State Privatization Report, February 2011. (Box 71, Folder 8)
      - Alcohol Beverage Control Handouts, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 9)
      - More Effective Position Level Management Reform Proposal (MEL's), undated. (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - Virginia Office of Protection and Advocacy, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - EHF Consulting: Howard Estes, 2011. (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - Public-Private Transportation Act, 2008. (Box 71, Folder 13)
      - Council on Virginia's Future: Regionalism: 1, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 14)
      - Council on Virginia's Future: Regionalism: 2, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 15)
      - Council on Virginia's Future, Virginia Reforms-Budget Priorities, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 16)
      - Older Dominion Partnership, 2010. (Box 71, Folder 17)
      - Time/Attendance Leave of Employees, 2011. (Box 71, Folder 18)
      - Government Reform, 2011. (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Government Reform (Files of Jeff Palmore)
      - Executive Reorganization Bills (1 of 3), 2011-2012. (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Executive Reorganization Bills (2 of 3), 2011-2012. (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - Executive Reorganization Bills (3 of 3), 2011-2012. (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Deregulation, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Deloitte Contract, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - VRS/VCSP Merged Investments, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - ICPRB, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Government Reform, Agency Mailings, undated. (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Government Reform, Leave, 2010-2011. (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Government Reform, Bonding Authority, 2007. (Box 72, Folder 10)
      - Government Reform, Grievance, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 11)
      - Government Reform Bill, 2011-2012. (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - Pre-Trial SVCS/Bail Bondsmen, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 13)
      - Government Reform Ideas, 2011. (Box 72, Folder 14)
      - Governor McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring (1 of 6), 2011-2012. (Box 72, Folder 15)
      - Governor McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring (2 of 6), 2011. (Box 72, Folder 16)
      - Governor McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring (3 of 6), 2011. (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Governor McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring (4 of 6), 2011-2012. (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Governor McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring (5 of 6), 2010. (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Governor McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring (6 of 6), 2011-2012. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2010. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Restoration of Rights, 2012-2013. (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Restoration of Rights-Gun Question, 2010-2011. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - School Safety Legislation, 2013. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Tax Reform, 2010-2011. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Texting and Driving, 2013. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Teddy Pierries Thompson, 2010-2011. (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Lottery, 2011. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Port Authority-Virginia International Terminals, Inc. Service Agreement, 1997. (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Retirement System (VRS) Reform (1 of 2), 2011-2012. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Retirement System (VRS) Reform (2 of 2), 2011. (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Subseries IV.C. Melissa Laughner, Deputy Director of Policy, 2008-2011., Extent: 0.7 cubic feet (2 boxes) (Box 76-77)
    This subseries is housed in two (2) boxes. The original order has been maintained. Melissa Laughner served as Deputy Director of Policy from January 2010 until March 2011. Laughner served as Policy Director for McDonnell's 2009 gubernatorial campaign. Prior to the campaign she was Special Assistant for Governmental Affairs in the Office of the Attorney General. Laughner was responsible for legislative, budgetary and programmatic policy evaluation and development for the McDonnell administration for the Secretariats of Agriculture and Forestry, Commerce and Trade, Education, Natural Resources, and Public Safety. Laughner also served as the primary liaison between the policy office and the Governor's Commission on Job Creation and Higher Education.
    - Massie Meeting, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Workforce Development, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Efficiency and Conservation, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Uranium, 2008. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - "Green" Renewable, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Performs, 2008. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Privatization, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Cost Savings, 2008-2009. (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Community Health Association, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Wellness Prevention, undated. (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Doug Bevelacqua, State Health Care Initiatives, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Deloitte - The Catalyst for Health Care Reform, undated. (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Medical Society of Virginia, Prevent a Crisis. Protect the Cap. For the Health of Virginia, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - CHIP of Virginia, 2009. (Box 76, Folder 14)